# Mali McCalla

TL;DR: A musician on a mission to revolutionise the music industry.

#### Skills | Experience | Side Projects | Education | Interests

As a musician I've been told that I think differently, in sounds and pictures rather than in words. Software development has always fascinated me, just like music it demands skills that combine logical problemsolving with creative thinking. In pursuit of a career founded on continuous self-improvement, I'm looking to join an ambitious team with a shared vision. After graduating from Europe's leading developer bootcamp in 2016 I now spend most of my time exploring new technologies and nesting callbacks chaining promises async/ awaiting.

# Skills

#### Collaboration

Working as a writer it was my job to collaborate with other people, to construct musical stories and relatable lyrics. In being able to see things from other peoples point of view I have learnt to make effective decisions based on both emotional reasoning and intuition. At the very core of every successful collaborative project I have ever worked on lies good communication, a skill that I once feared but have come to master over time. Working in a team has enabled me to create some of my best work.

### **Creative thinking**

A big part of what attracts me to coding is that it presents new challenges in all shapes and sizes. My ability to apply creative thinking in both a digital and non-digital environment allows me to tackle these challenges from a different perspective. Not afraid to take chances, I know that in an ever changing tech industry you need to be able explore innovative and original ways to go about solving problems.

# Experience

### **JAAK (Apr 2018 - Jun 2019)**

## https://jaak.io

In the ever changing web development landscape my role as a Javascript Engineer at JAAK was forever evolving.

#### **Technologies**

- Ethereum/Solidity
- · React/Next.js
- Node/Express
- Apollo GraphQL
- AWS
- TypeScript

- HTML/CSS3
- Jest/Cypress

### **Trippin (Sep 2017 - Apr 2018)**

### https://trippin.world

I was one half of the development team tasked to build the Trippin travel app. With React Native as my choice of weapon I stepped up to the job a took the app from design/concept stage all the way to production.

## **Technologies**

- React/React Native
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- CSS-in-JS
- GraphQL
- Flow

## Warner Brothers Entertainment (Dec 2010 - Dec 2015)

Working as both an artist signed to Warner Brothers Records and a writer published by Warner Chappel I gained a variety priceless skills and expertise.

- **People management**: In charge of organising and managing various tours with various musicians I learnt the importance of becoming a great listener and being able to relate to others.
- **Discipline**: Over the years as a published songwriter I taught myself to play 6 instruments to the highest of standards. I now approach every new challenge with a great amount of discipline and tenacity.

Throughout my time at Warner, I built up amazing relationships and achieved many great things. One of my proudest moments was being awarded a 2x platinum plaque by BPI for sales in excess of 600,000 for my song on the Chase and Status album 'No More Idols'.

### **Touring - Various artists (2013 - Present)**

Touring around the world brought upon many unpredictable challenges to overcome. It brought out a determination in me to succeed in a very competitive industry. A skill that I now take into every new challenge I face. I became an expert time manager and learnt how to focus my time and energy with ruthless efficiency. My most recent work in this area has been singing around the world with Rudimental including our support of Ed Sheeran on his sold out stadium world tour.

# Side Projects

Project Description Tech

Project	Description	Tech
Shuttle	An Itinerary app for touring musicians. Having a keen interest in server-less technologies, I wanted to explore how I could utilise cloud computing and google's firebase to create an app which was useable on both android and iOS.	Mobile, React Native, Redux, Firebase
Codey Gonzalez	A speed type racer for keen coders. Participating in a 3 day hackathon myself and a team of 4 were tasked with creating an efficiency tool for developers. Channelling the full power of Javascript we were successful in creating a fun and user-friendly experience. Try it out on Heroku.	Ruby, JQuery, Postgres
Tunebay	A way to connect with and directly support the music you love. Tunebay is built putting UX first. A lightweight yet robust Express server coupled with a React front end that securely communicates with S3.	React, Redux, Express, Node.js, AWS, Postgres
Flare	An app for discovering amazing moments around you. With no prior knowledge of Swift or XCode myself and a team of 5 built a fully functional social app. Following agile principles and best practices we finish our MVP within just 8 days. You can watch a demo of the app Here, or even Download it on the app store!	iOS, Swift, Objective- C, Xcode

# Education

# Makers Academy (Jul — Sep 2016)

- 12 week, full-time computer programming course based on the principles of software craftsmanship
- Focus on writing clean, test-driven code.
- · Object-oriented design, abiding by SOLID principles
- Team work based on Agile development

## **British Academy Of New Music (2009 - 2011)**

BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma (Equivalent to three A-Levels)

• A course that stretched me in all aspects of music performance, composition, engineering and production.

## **Highgate Woods Performing Arts College (2004 - 2009)**

11 GCSEs all at A\* - B

# Interests

• Aerodynamics has always fascinated me and I am currently working towards my private pilots licence with 16 logged hours to date.

• In my spare time I have been writing a short comedy script portraying the modern day music industry.

- Experiencing new cultures
- 🗶

# disclaimer:

Sometimes I know things and sometimes I don't. I'm ok with that because at *all times* I work on moving the latter to the former (and if all fails there's probably an npm package for it ).